<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Sports</string>
    <string name="list_fragment_label">Sports</string>
    <string name="detail_fragment_label">Sport Info</string>

    <string name="baseball">Baseball</string>
    <string name="badminton">Badminton</string>
    <string name="basketball">Basketball</string>
    <string name="bowling">Bowling</string>
    <string name="cycling">Cycling</string>
    <string name="golf">Golf</string>
    <string name="running">Running</string>
    <string name="soccer">Soccer</string>
    <string name="swimming">Swimming</string>
    <string name="table_tennis">Table Tennis</string>
    <string name="tennis">Tennis</string>

    <string name="baseball_list_subtitle">Played with a bat and ball by two teams aiming to score runs by hitting and running on a field.</string>
    <string name="badminton_list_subtitle">A fast-paced racquet sport, where players use a shuttlecock to score points by hitting it over a net.</string>
    <string name="basketball_list_subtitle">Played on a court, where two teams aim to score points by shooting a ball through a hoop.</string>
    <string name="bowling_list_subtitle">Players roll a heavy ball down a lane to knock down pins arranged in a triangular formation.</string>
    <string name="cycling_list_subtitle">Cycling is a sport that involves riding bicycles, typically on roads or off-road trails.</string>
    <string name="golf_list_subtitle">Golf is a sport played on a course, where players aim to get a ball into holes in as few strokes as possible.</string>
    <string name="running_list_subtitle">Running is a sport and exercise where individuals move rapidly on foot, often in races of varying distances.</string>
    <string name="soccer_list_subtitle">A team sport played on a field where two teams aim to score goals by kicking a ball into the net.</string>
    <string name="swimming_list_subtitle">Swimming is a water sport where people move through water using different strokes.</string>
    <string name="table_tennis_list_subtitle">A fast-paced indoor sport with small paddles and a lightweight ball played over a table.</string>
    <string name="tennis_list_subtitle">Tennis is a racquet sport played on a court, with players scoring points by hitting a ball over a net.</string>

    <string name="baseball_detail_text">
        The history of baseball is a journey that spans centuries, evolving from a simple
        bat-and-ball game into a complex sport deeply embedded in American culture and embraced
        worldwide. Its roots can be traced back to various bat-and-ball games played in Europe, but
        it took on a distinctive form in North America during the 18th and 19th centuries.
        \n\n
        In the mid-19th century, baseball began to take shape as clubs and organizations established
        rules and regulations. The Knickerbocker Base Ball Club in New York is often credited with
        codifying many of the sport\'s rules in 1845, including the diamond-shaped field and the
        nine-player team format. By the late 19th century, baseball had grown in popularity and
        professionalism, with the formation of the National League in 1876 as the first major
        professional baseball league.
        \n\n
        The late 19th and early 20th centuries witnessed the rise of iconic players like Babe Ruth,
        whose prowess as a power hitter changed the game and captured the imagination of fans. The
        \"Black Sox\" scandal of 1919, in which several Chicago White Sox players conspired to fix the
        World Series, highlighted the need for better governance and integrity in the sport. This
        led to the establishment of the Office of the Commissioner of Baseball, which helped restore
        public trust.
        \n\n
        The sport continued to evolve with the inclusion of African American players, most notably
        Jackie Robinson, who broke the color barrier when he joined the Brooklyn Dodgers in 1947.
        This marked a significant milestone in the fight for racial equality and expanded the talent
        pool of baseball players. In the following decades, players like Hank Aaron, Willie Mays,
        and Roberto Clemente became legends of the game.
        \n\n
        Baseball\'s global appeal grew as well, with the establishment of international competitions
        like the World Baseball Classic. Today, baseball remains a beloved sport in the
        United States, Japan, Latin America, and many other countries, with Major League Baseball
        (MLB) serving as the pinnacle of professional play. Its rich history, iconic players, and
        enduring popularity make baseball a timeless and cherished part of sports history.
    </string>

    <string name="badminton_detail_text">
        The history of badminton is a rich tapestry that dates back centuries, with its origins
        tracing to ancient civilizations. The game evolved from various ancient forms of shuttlecock
        sports, with roots in cultures as diverse as India, China, and Greece.
        \n\n
        One of the earliest forms of badminton was played in India, where it was known as \"Poona\"
        due to its popularity in Pune. British army officers stationed in India in the mid-19th
        century encountered the game and brought it back to England. They introduced it to their
        friends and played it in their leisure time, eventually formalizing the rules. In 1873,
        badminton was officially introduced in England when the Bath Badminton Club published the
        first official rules of the game, and it quickly gained popularity.
        \n\n
        The sport further evolved when the Duke of Beaufort\'s Badminton House hosted the first
        official badminton tournament in 1877. The game was initially played with a wooden
        shuttlecock and called \"Poona,\" but as it gained popularity in England, the name \"badminton\"
        was adopted, derived from the Duke\'s estate.
        \n\n
        Badminton continued to develop and grow as a popular recreational activity, and it gained
        international recognition with the formation of the Badminton Association of England in
        1893. The first All England Championships took place in 1899, marking the birth of
        competitive badminton. As the sport expanded globally, the first international tournament
        was held between England and Ireland in 1903.
        \n\n
        In 1934, the International Badminton Federation (now the Badminton World Federation) was
        founded, overseeing the sport\'s global development. Badminton became an Olympic sport in
        1992, further solidifying its status on the world stage. Today, it is played and enjoyed by
        millions of people worldwide, with professional tournaments, including the prestigious All
        England Open Badminton Championships, showcasing top talent and skill in the sport. The
        history of badminton is a testament to its enduring appeal and evolution from a leisure
        activity to a highly competitive sport.
    </string>
    <string name="basketball_detail_text">
        The history of basketball is a captivating journey that began in the late 19th century and
        has since become one of the most popular and widely played sports in the world. Its
        invention is credited to Dr. James Naismith, a Canadian physical education instructor, who
        created the game in December 1891 in Springfield, Massachusetts, as a way to keep his
        students active during the winter months.
        \n\n
        Naismith\'s original concept involved nailing a peach basket onto the wall of a gymnasium
        and using a soccer ball. The objective was to score points by throwing the ball into the
        opposing team\'s basket while following a set of basic rules. This rudimentary version of
        basketball quickly gained popularity, and the first official game was played on January 20,
        1892.
        \n\n
        The game\'s growth was rapid, and the first official basketball match outside the United
        States occurred in 1893 in Ontario, Canada. Soon after, colleges and universities began
        adopting basketball as a sport, leading to the formation of the first college basketball
        league in 1901. The game\'s popularity continued to soar, culminating in the establishment
        of the National Basketball Association (NBA) in 1946 as the premier professional basketball
        league in the United States.
        \n\n
        Basketball also played a significant role in the Olympics, with the sport making its debut
        at the 1936 Summer Olympics in Berlin. The United States dominated the early Olympic
        basketball tournaments, showcasing the nation\'s talent and passion for the sport. Over time,
        the Olympics became a global stage for the best basketball talent from around the world.
        \n\n
        The sport continued to evolve in terms of rules and equipment, with innovations such as the
        shot clock introduced in 1954 to increase the pace of the game. Legendary players like
        Michael Jordan, Larry Bird, Magic Johnson, and LeBron James further fueled the sport\'s
        popularity, elevating basketball to a global phenomenon. Today, basketball is played at
        various levels, from local pick-up games to professional leagues worldwide, with the NBA
        being one of the most-watched sports leagues globally. Its rich history and dynamic nature
        make basketball a timeless and cherished part of sports culture.
    </string>
    <string name="bowling_detail_text">
        Bowling, a classic leisure activity and competitive sport, has a history that stretches back
        thousands of years. The origins of bowling can be traced to ancient civilizations, with some
        of the earliest forms of the game discovered in Egyptian tombs dating back to around 3200
        BCE. These ancient versions often involved rolling stones or wooden objects to knock down
        other objects, much like modern bowling.
        \n\n
        The game of bowling as we know it today began to take shape in Europe during the
        Middle Ages. In Germany, a form of bowling called \"kegeln\" was popular, using nine pins
        arranged in a diamond pattern. Over time, this evolved into the ten-pin bowling we\'re
        familiar with today. By the 19th century, bowling had made its way to the United States,
        where it gained popularity, especially among German immigrants.
        \n\n
        In 1895, the American Bowling Congress (ABC) was formed, establishing standardized rules and
        regulations for the game. The ten-pin format became the standard in the United States, with
        the distinctive setup of ten pins arranged in a triangle at the end of a wooden lane.
        Bowling alleys began to proliferate across the country, and the sport became a popular
        form of entertainment.
        \n\n
        The introduction of automatic pin-setting machines in the 1950s revolutionized the game,
        making it more accessible and efficient. This development led to the growth of bowling as
        both a recreational pastime and a competitive sport. Leagues and tournaments became
        commonplace, and professional bowling emerged as a popular televised sport in the
        mid-20th century.
        \n\n
        Today, bowling remains a beloved activity enjoyed by people of all ages and skill levels.
        It combines elements of strategy, precision, and camaraderie, making it a social sport as
        well as a competitive one. Professional bowling tours, such as the Professional Bowlers
        Association (PBA) Tour, showcase top-level talent, and bowling alleys continue to be a
        gathering place for friends and families to enjoy a game together. Bowling\'s enduring appeal
        and rich history make it a cherished part of leisure and sports culture worldwide.
    </string>
    <string name="cycling_detail_text">
        The history of cycling is a fascinating journey through time, spanning centuries of
        innovation and evolution. The origins of cycling can be traced back to the early 19th
        century when various inventors and tinkerers began experimenting with pedal-powered
        machines. One of the earliest documented examples is the draisine or \"running machine\"
        invented by Karl Drais in 1817, which featured a wooden frame and handlebars but lacked pedals.
        \n\n
        The development of the pedal-driven bicycle took a significant leap forward in the 1860s
        with the creation of the \"boneshaker\" or velocipede. These early bicycles featured iron or
        wooden frames, solid rubber tires, and pedals attached directly to the front wheel. Despite
        their uncomfortable ride and nickname, they became popular in the 1860s and 1870s.
        \n\n
        In the 1870s, the introduction of the high-wheel bicycle, also known as the penny-farthing
        due to its large front wheel and small rear wheel, marked another milestone in cycling
        history. This design allowed for greater speed but was dangerous and impractical for many
        riders. However, it paved the way for the development of the \"safety bicycle\" in the 1880s,
        featuring a chain drive system that connected the pedals to the rear wheel. This design made
        cycling more accessible and led to a surge in popularity.
        \n\n
        By the late 19th century, cycling had become a global phenomenon. The formation of cycling
        clubs, the standardization of rules, and the organization of competitive races, such as the
        Tour de France in 1903, contributed to the sport\'s growth. The bicycle also played a pivotal
        role in transportation, offering an affordable and efficient means of getting around for
        many people.
        \n\n
        In the 20th century, cycling continued to evolve with innovations like the derailleur gear
        system, which allowed riders to shift gears easily. The development of mountain biking in
        the 1970s and the growth of competitive road racing, track cycling, and BMX added diversity
        to the sport. Today, cycling encompasses a wide range of disciplines, from leisurely rides
        to high-speed racing, and it remains a popular form of transportation, recreation, and
        competition worldwide. Its history is a testament to human ingenuity and the enduring appeal
        of two-wheeled travel.
    </string>
    <string name="golf_detail_text">
        The history of golf is a storied journey that spans centuries and continents, reflecting the
        evolution of the sport from its humble origins to its status as a beloved global pastime.
        While the exact origins of golf are debated, it is widely believed to have originated in
        Scotland during the late Middle Ages. Early forms of the game involved hitting a ball with a
        stick or club across rough terrain toward a target, such as a tree or a hole, in as few
        strokes as possible.
        \n\n
        One of the earliest documented mentions of golf dates back to 1457 when King James II of
        Scotland banned the sport, as it was seen as a distraction from military training. However,
        golf\'s popularity persisted, and it continued to be played on the rugged Scottish linksland.
        The term \"golf\" itself is believed to have originated from the Dutch word \"kolf,\" meaning
        club or bat.
        \n\n
        The first recorded rules of golf were established in 1744 at the Honorable Company of
        Edinburgh Golfers. These rules laid the foundation for modern golf, including the use of an
        18-hole course and standardized equipment. The Royal and Ancient Golf Club of St. Andrews,
        founded in 1754, played a crucial role in codifying the sport\'s rules and regulations.
        \n\n
        Golf experienced significant growth in the 19th century, particularly in the United Kingdom
        and the United States. The development of the gutta-percha ball in the mid-1800s, replacing
        the featherie ball, led to a more consistent and affordable golf ball. Golf clubs and
        courses proliferated, and the sport became accessible to a wider range of players.
        \n\n
        The 20th century saw the expansion of professional golf, with the establishment of major
        tournaments such as The Open Championship, the U.S. Open, the Masters Tournament, and the
        PGA Championship. Legendary golfers like Bobby Jones, Jack Nicklaus, Arnold Palmer, and
        Tiger Woods became household names and played pivotal roles in popularizing the sport.
        Today, golf is enjoyed by millions of players worldwide, and it continues to evolve with
        advancements in technology and a growing global fanbase. Its history is a testament to the
        enduring appeal of the pursuit of precision and the beauty of the greens.
    </string>
    <string name="running_detail_text">
        The history of running is a tale as old as humanity itself, rooted in our evolutionary
        development as bipedal creatures. Running, in its simplest form, has been a crucial skill for
        survival and transportation for millions of years, allowing early humans to hunt, gather,
        and explore their environments.
        \n\n
        Throughout history, running played a pivotal role in various civilizations and cultures. In
        ancient Greece, the Olympic Games, first held in 776 BCE, included running events like the
        stadion, a short sprint of approximately 200 meters. These early competitions laid the
        foundation for organized running as a sport.
        \n\n
        The marathon, one of the most iconic long-distance races, has its origins in ancient Greece
        as well. Legend has it that in 490 BCE, a Greek soldier named Pheidippides ran from the
        battlefield of Marathon to Athens, a distance of about 26.2 miles (42.2 kilometers), to
        deliver news of a military victory. This event inspired the modern marathon race, which made
        its debut at the 1896 Athens Olympics.
        \n\n
        In the 19th and 20th centuries, organized road racing gained popularity, with events like
        the Boston Marathon (first held in 1897) and the Olympic Games contributing to the sport\'s
        growth. Track and field competitions also became a staple of the modern Olympics, with
        sprinters, middle-distance runners, and long-distance athletes achieving international
        acclaim.
        \n\n
        The running boom of the 1970s and 1980s, ignited by events like the New York City Marathon
        and the emergence of running as a recreational activity, transformed running into a global
        phenomenon. The development of sports science, training methodologies, and advancements in
        running shoe technology further elevated the sport. Today, running encompasses a wide range
        of disciplines, from sprinting and middle-distance racing to ultramarathons and trail
        running, and it continues to inspire individuals of all ages and abilities to lace up their
        shoes and hit the road or trail. The history of running is a testament to our enduring
        connection with this fundamental and empowering form of physical activity.
    </string>
    <string name="soccer_detail_text">
        The history of soccer, also known as football in most parts of the world, is a story that
        unfolds over centuries, tracing its origins to ancient civilizations. Ball games resembling
        soccer were played by various cultures, such as the Greeks and Romans, as far back as 300 BCE.
        These early versions of the game involved kicking a ball toward a designated target or goal.
        \n\n
        However, it was in medieval England that the sport began to take on its modern form. In the
        12th century, a game called \"mob football\" was popular in English towns and villages, where
        teams would compete to move a ball from one landmark to another. The rules were often
        chaotic, and the game could be violent and unruly.
        \n\n
        In the 19th century, the need for standardized rules became evident. In 1863, the Football
        Association (FA) was founded in England, marking a crucial moment in soccer history. The FA
        established the fundamental rules of the game, including the prohibition of using hands to
        touch the ball (except by goalkeepers) and the creation of a rectangular field with goalposts
        at each end. These rules formed the basis for modern soccer.
        \n\n
        Soccer rapidly spread beyond England\'s borders, gaining popularity across Europe and South
        America. International matches began to take place, with England hosting Scotland in the
        first-ever international game in 1872. The sport continued to evolve, with the formation of
        domestic leagues and the inclusion of soccer in the first modern Olympic Games in 1900.
        \n\n
        The pinnacle of international soccer came with the establishment of the FIFA World Cup in
        1930, which has since become the most prestigious and widely watched soccer tournament in
        the world. Iconic players like Pelé, Diego Maradona, and Lionel Messi have left indelible
        marks on the sport, captivating fans with their skill and artistry.
        \n\n
        Today, soccer stands as the most popular sport globally, with millions of players and fans
        in virtually every corner of the world. From the grassroots level to the highest professional
        leagues, soccer\'s rich history is a testament to its ability to transcend cultural and
        geographical boundaries, uniting people in the love of the beautiful game.
    </string>
    <string name="swimming_detail_text">
        The history of swimming can be traced back thousands of years to ancient civilizations,
        where it was not only a recreational activity but also an essential survival skill.
        Ancient depictions of swimming can be found in cave paintings and records from civilizations
        such as the Egyptians, Greeks, and Romans. Swimming was often practiced for military purposes,
        transportation, and religious ceremonies.
        \n\n
        In the 19th century, swimming as a sport began to gain recognition and structure.
        The National Swimming Society was established in London in 1837, and competitive swimming
        events were organized with standardized rules. The sport continued to evolve, and swimming
        was included in the inaugural modern Olympic Games in 1896, marking a significant milestone
        in its history.
        \n\n
        Today, swimming is a popular recreational activity and competitive sport practiced worldwide.
        Competitive swimming encompasses various strokes, each with its own technique and characteristics.
        The four primary swimming strokes are:
        \n\n
        1. Freestyle (Front Crawl): Freestyle is the fastest and most common stroke used in
        competitive swimming. Swimmers use a flutter kick and alternating arm strokes to move
        forward while keeping their face in the water. Breathing is typically done by turning the
        head to the side during arm strokes.
        \n
        2. Backstroke: In backstroke, swimmers lie on their backs and use an alternating flutter
        kick and rotating arm strokes. Unlike other strokes, the face remains out of the water,
        and swimmers must rely on timing to breathe properly.
        \n
        3. Breaststroke: Breaststroke is known for its unique frog-like leg motion, where both legs
        move simultaneously in a circular motion. The arms move in a coordinated manner, with an
        initial pull, followed by a simultaneous arm sweep and recovery. Swimmers must breathe by
        lifting their head out of the water during each arm stroke cycle.
        \n
        4. Butterfly: Butterfly is considered one of the most challenging and physically demanding
        strokes. Swimmers use an undulating dolphin kick and simultaneous arm strokes that come out
        of the water to propel themselves forward. Breathing is typically done by lifting the head
        out of the water during the arm recovery phase.
        \n\n
        These strokes form the basis of competitive swimming events, with each having its own set of
        distances and individual medley (IM) events, where swimmers must perform all four strokes in
        a specific order. The history of swimming and the development of these strokes have
        contributed to the sport\'s enduring popularity, both as a means of recreation and as a
        highly competitive athletic endeavor.
    </string>
    <string name="table_tennis_detail_text">
        The history of table tennis, also known as ping pong, is a relatively recent one compared
        to many other sports, but it has quickly become a beloved pastime and competitive activity
        worldwide. The roots of table tennis can be traced back to England in the late 19th century,
        where it was initially played as an indoor version of lawn tennis. Early versions of the
        game used makeshift equipment, including cigar box lids as paddles and rounded wine corks
        as balls.
        \n\n
        The name \"ping pong\" originated as an onomatopoeic term for the sound made by the ball
        hitting the table and the paddles. In the early 20th century, the sport gained popularity,
        and several companies began marketing ping pong equipment. The first official table tennis
        tournament was held in 1902, and the game\'s rules were gradually standardized.
        \n\n
        Table tennis quickly spread beyond England, with Europe and Asia becoming major hubs for the
        sport. In the 1920s, the International Table Tennis Federation (ITTF) was established, with
        the sport\'s first official world championships taking place in London in 1926. The ITTF
        played a pivotal role in promoting and regulating table tennis on the global stage.
        \n\n
        During the mid-20th century, table tennis experienced a surge in popularity, with
        international competitions becoming increasingly competitive. The sport made its Olympic
        debut at the 1988 Seoul Olympics and has been a regular Olympic event since. The rapid pace,
        precision, and skill required in table tennis have captivated both recreational players and
        professional athletes alike.
        \n\n
        Today, table tennis is enjoyed by millions of players of all ages and skill levels worldwide.
        It is known for its fast-paced rallies, spin techniques, and lightning-quick reflexes.
        Professional players from countries like China have dominated the international scene,
        showcasing extraordinary talent and agility. The history of table tennis is a testament to
        the sport\'s universal appeal, its journey from humble beginnings to a global phenomenon,
        and its status as an Olympic sport that continues to captivate enthusiasts around the world.
    </string>
    <string name="tennis_detail_text">
        The history of tennis is a tale that spans centuries and continents, reflecting the
        evolution of a sport that has captured the hearts of players and fans worldwide. Tennis can
        trace its origins back to various ancient ball games played across cultures, but it began to
        take a more recognizable form in medieval France. In the 12th century, a game called
        \"jeu de paume\" (game of the palm) was popular, played with the hand or a glove, often in
        courtyards or against church walls.
        \n\n
        The term \"tennis\" is believed to have originated from the French word \"tenez,\" which means
        \"take heed\" or \"receive.\" In this game, one player would serve the ball, and the opponent
        would attempt to return it. Tennis began to spread across Europe, with variations in rules
        and equipment, and it became a favorite pastime among nobility and aristocrats.
        \n\n
        In the 16th century, tennis underwent a transformation with the introduction of rackets,
        allowing players to hit the ball with more power and precision. The sport was played in
        indoor courts, and it gained popularity in England, where it was known as \"real tennis.\"
        This form of tennis had intricate rules, and each court was unique, which made it a sport
        primarily for the elite.
        \n\n
        The modern version of lawn tennis, which most people are familiar with today, emerged in the
        late 19th century in England. Major Walter Clopton Wingfield is often credited with
        popularizing the outdoor version of tennis. He published the first set of standardized rules
        for lawn tennis in 1874, and the game soon spread across the British Empire and to the
        United States.
        \n\n
        The first Wimbledon Championships, one of the most prestigious tennis tournaments in the
        world, took place in 1877. Lawn tennis quickly gained popularity worldwide, and tennis
        clubs and associations were established to govern the sport. The Davis Cup, the world\'s
        premier international team tennis competition, was inaugurated in 1900.
        \n\n
        Tennis made its Olympic debut at the 1896 Athens Games and has been a part of the Summer
        Olympics ever since. Over the years, tennis has seen legendary players like Rod Laver,
        Bjorn Borg, Martina Navratilova, Serena Williams, Roger Federer, and Rafael Nadal, who
        have contributed to its rich history and global appeal. Today, tennis is played at
        various levels, from grassroots to the professional tour, and it continues to captivate
        fans with its thrilling matches and iconic moments.
    </string>

    <plurals name="player_count_caption">
        <item quantity="one">1 Player</item>
        <item quantity="other">%1$d Players</item>
    </plurals>
    <string name="olympic_caption">Olympic</string>

    <string name="back_button">Back</string>
</resources>